<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Attention is all you need</title>
    <link href="/2022/02/01/Attention/"/>
    <url>/2022/02/01/Attention/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="front">Front</h1><p>The fundamental hypothesis behind NLP is the belife of a universal space called "semantic". Any natural language can be transferred into the space on a uniform scale. For the task of machine translation, the only processes we need are to <strong>encode</strong> language A to the space, then <strong>decode</strong> the semantic representations back to language B.</p><ul><li><p>RNN However, there is no way for us the encode/decode sentences directedly as a whole. We need an efficient heuristic to achieve it one word by one word, which is the truth that we reading and writing from left to right. Therefore, RNN came up. It roughly <strong>accumulates</strong> the <strong>words relationships</strong> into the current <strong>context representation</strong> as current <strong>hidden state</strong>, which is expected to be the vectors in "semantic space", and uses it to predict the next word. RNN has the drawback of precluding parallized training in batches for its inherently sequantial nature.</p></li><li><p>LSTM People find that not all words are important to the context representation, so that we should not simply accumulate it. LSTM introduces cell states to control contributions of components of <strong>context representation</strong>: current word and previous context. Although LSTM was originally designed to solve the problem of information loss when decoding long sentences, it indicates that we should calculate the context representation in a selective way.</p></li><li><p>Attention Attention is proposed to decode the final context selectively in terms of words in the translated sentence. To do it, we need weights between the current input of decoder and all words in the translated sentence. It's natural that we can use hidden states of both encoder and decoder to represent corresponding words, and then calculat the weight by FCNets followed by a softmax. This process is actually a qury-key matching. Instead of using the hidden states as qury, key and value, we use FCNets to generate them, preventing from confusing the network. <span class="math display">\[k_i = W_kh_i\&amp;v_i = W_vh_i\&amp;q_j = W_qs_j\&amp;\]</span></p></li></ul><p><span class="math display">\[\begin{equation} \label{eq2}\begin{aligned}a &amp;= b + c \\  &amp;= d + e + f + g \\  &amp;= h + i\end{aligned}\end{equation}\]</span></p><p>Suppose we are decoding <span class="math inline">\(j^{th}\)</span> words. Denoting the hidden state of previous words that already predicted as <span class="math inline">\(s_{j-1}\)</span>, and that of words in the translated sentence as <span class="math inline">\(h_{i}\)</span>. We call <span class="math inline">\(s_{j-1}\)</span> a qury, and <span class="math inline">\(h_{i}\)</span> keys.</p><p>It is designed to aggreate words relationships, so that we need a measurement of words relationship. The concept of <strong>key</strong> arises. Indeed we can use the semantic representations to calculate the relationships by simple methods like cosine similary or FCNet. Researchers however shows extra keies are suprior than those simple measurements.</p><h1 id="journey">Journey</h1><h2 id="background">background</h2><ul><li>[-] LSTM is popular at that time, but has disadvantages: factor computation along the symbol positions. This inherently sequential nature reasonably catch up words dependencies, but preclude parallelization training.</li><li>[+] Attention mechanisms allow catch up words dependencies without regard to positions.</li><li>[o] Attention mechanisms however are in conjunction with RNN in current fashions. <strong>Purpose 1.</strong> Why not throw RNN away? Just use attention.</li><li>[-] Sequential computation is heavy.</li><li>[+] CNN computation is light. But current models are still computational intensive, which is factored to words distances. <strong>Purpose 2.</strong> Come up a method insetad of convolution, and keep a costant computation without regard to words distances.</li></ul><h2 id="solution-1.0">solution 1.0</h2><p><strong>Purpose 1.</strong> Build the Transformer (see Design)</p><p><strong>Purpose 2.</strong> averaging attention-weighted positions</p><h2 id="challenge-1.0">challenge 1.0</h2><p><strong>Purpose 2.</strong> reduced effective resolution</p><h2 id="solution-2.0">solution 2.0</h2><p><strong>Purpose 2.</strong> Multi-Head Attention</p><h1 id="design">Design</h1><h2 id="feature">feature</h2><ul><li>encoder-decoder style</li><li>stacked self-attention</li><li>point-wise fully connected layers</li></ul><p>Q: 当我在decode的时候，用于decode当前单词j的hidden source就叫做Q_i K: encode完成后，每一个单词的hidden embedding就叫做K_i V: encode完成后，每一个 # Re-think</p><h1 id="my-thought">My thought</h1><!-- <div class="markdown-body"></div> -->]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Paper review</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>NLP</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="/2022/02/01/hello-world/"/>
    <url>/2022/02/01/hello-world/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a href="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html">troubleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues">GitHub</a>.</p><h2 id="quick-start">Quick Start</h2><h3 id="create-a-new-post">Create a new post</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><div class="code-wrapper"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></div></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo new <span class="hljs-string">&quot;My New Post&quot;</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html">Writing</a></p><h3 id="run-server">Run server</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo server<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html">Server</a></p><h3 id="generate-static-files">Generate static files</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo generate<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html">Generating</a></p><h3 id="deploy-to-remote-sites">Deploy to remote sites</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo deploy<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/one-command-deployment.html">Deployment</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
